<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forecasting | Academic</title>
    <link>/tags/forecasting/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/forecasting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Forecasting</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Francisco Rowe 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Forecasting</title>
      <link>/tags/forecasting/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID19 Generating actionable evidence for containing misinformation to prevent discrimination</title>
      <link>/project/covid19_misinformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/covid19_misinformation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our project will generate fundamental and timely evidence for how misinformation and
fake news spreads across media platforms in the UK, and how this impacts experiences of discrimination associated with Covid-19. Novel text mining and data science approaches will be applied to investigate patterns in the reporting of Covid-19 in the news/media, as well as across social media. We will identify the structure of terminology used in how Covid-19 is reported, including measuring the use of emotion of language through sentiment analysis. Network science techniques will study the flows of information across social media to identify how they spread, as well identify leverage points to stem flows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using satellite imagery to measure the evolution of cities</title>
      <link>/project/satellite_cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/satellite_cities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sustainable urban habitats are a key component of global challenges, and efficient management and planning of cities are pivotal to all 17 UN SDGs. Over 90% of projected urban growth by 2050 will occur in less developed countries. Prior work on urbanisation has identified the benefits of agglomeration and improvements in health and education, which tend to outweigh the costs of congestion, pollution and poverty. Yet research has focused on Western cities: urban areas with high-income, in developed countries. Much less is known about urban habitats in less developed countries. This project aims to improve our understanding of urban areas levearing on large scale satellite imagery and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Subnational Population Forecasts</title>
      <link>/project/population_forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/population_forecast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Improving Sub-national Population Forecasts. The aim of this project is to make significant advances in two related areas of regional, council area and local population forecasting, namely improving accuracy, and providing an indication of forecast uncertainty. Population forecasts often turn out to be far more inaccurate than users realise and fail to come with any information about reliability. Every year forecasts inform a wide variety of planning and policy development activities and influence investment decisions worth billions of dollars. In order to increase the value of forecasts to users, this project aims to combine methods from a range of disciplines to devise more accurate ways of forecasting populations, and provide accompanying information on their likely error.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
