<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immigration | Academic</title>
    <link>/tags/immigration/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/immigration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Immigration</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Francisco Rowe 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Immigration</title>
      <link>/tags/immigration/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Predicting the Long-term Labour Market and Migration Trajectories of Immigrants and Their Children in the United Kingdom</title>
      <link>/project/immigrants_trajectories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/immigrants_trajectories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior empirical research has advanced our understanding of immigrants’ assimilation, their descendants and the role of ethnic concentration. Yet work has remained cross-sectional in nature, focusing on the occupational outcomes and residential locations at a specific point in time. Little progress has been made to understand the trajectories of immigrants and their children over a long period of time. Understanding of the long-term trajectories of immigrants and their children is key to assess their prospects for economic and social success, and develop effective policy interventions to assist their integration process, unleash their skills’ potential and facilitate upward social mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using large scale social media data to measure perceptions towards immigration</title>
      <link>/project/bigdata_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/bigdata_perception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been nominated as an expert and project leader for the upcoming BIGSSS Summer School in Computational Social Science on Social Cohesion in Groningen, Netherlands.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bigsss-css.jacobs-university.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://bigsss-css.jacobs-university.de/&lt;/a&gt;. I will be leading a project on using twitter data and computational approaches to measure social cohesion and attitudes towards immigration. The project seeks to offer participants of the BIGSSS Summer Schools in Computational Social Science the opportunity to build on our experience in the use of Twitter data and machine learning to model and enhance the understanding of social cohesion and attitudes towards immigration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in attitudes towards immigration between Australia and Germany. The role of immigration policy</title>
      <link>/publication/cpos2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/cpos2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
