<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Francisco Rowe 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career trajectories and outcomes of forced migrants in Sweden. Self-employment, employment or persistent inactivity?</title>
      <link>/publication/sme2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/sme2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trends in multimorbidity, complex multimorbidity and multiple functional limitations in the ageing population of England, 2002–2015</title>
      <link>/publication/jc2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/jc2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scalable Analytical Framework for Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Neighborhood Change A Sequence Analysis Approach</title>
      <link>/publication/agile2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/agile2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hierarchical Urban Forest Index Using Street-Level Imagery and Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/rs2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/rs2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social determinants of multimorbidity and multiple functional limitations among the ageing population of England, 2002–2015</title>
      <link>/publication/ssm2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ssm2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Jupyter Notebooks with Academic</title>
      <link>/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from IPython.core.display import Image
Image(&#39;https://www.python.org/static/community_logos/python-logo-master-v3-TM-flattened.png&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./index_1_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;print(&amp;quot;Welcome to Academic!&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Welcome to Academic!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-python-and-jupyterlab&#34;&gt;Install Python and JupyterLab&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/#download-section&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Anaconda&lt;/a&gt; which includes Python 3 and JupyterLab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, install JupyterLab with &lt;code&gt;pip3 install jupyterlab&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-or-upload-a-jupyter-notebook&#34;&gt;Create or upload a Jupyter notebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands in your Terminal, substituting &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;MY-WEBSITE-FOLDER&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;SHORT-POST-TITLE&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with the file path to your Academic website folder and a short title for your blog post (use hyphens instead of spaces), respectively:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;mkdir -p &amp;lt;MY-WEBSITE-FOLDER&amp;gt;/content/post/&amp;lt;SHORT-POST-TITLE&amp;gt;/
cd &amp;lt;MY-WEBSITE-FOLDER&amp;gt;/content/post/&amp;lt;SHORT-POST-TITLE&amp;gt;/
jupyter lab index.ipynb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jupyter&lt;/code&gt; command above will launch the JupyterLab editor, allowing us to add Academic metadata and write the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;edit-your-post-metadata&#34;&gt;Edit your post metadata&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first cell of your Jupter notebook will contain your post metadata (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/front-matter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jupter, choose &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; as the type of the first cell and wrap your Academic metadata in three dashes, indicating that it is YAML front matter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
title: My post&#39;s title
date: 2019-09-01

# Put any other Academic metadata here...
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit the metadata of your post, using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; as a guide to the available options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#featured-image&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;featured image&lt;/a&gt;, place an image named &lt;code&gt;featured&lt;/code&gt; into your post&amp;rsquo;s folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other tips, such as using math, see the guide on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;writing content with Academic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;convert-notebook-to-markdown&#34;&gt;Convert notebook to Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jupyter nbconvert index.ipynb --to markdown --NbConvertApp.output_files_dir=.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was created with Jupyter. The orginal files can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite/content/post/jupyter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite/content/post/jupyter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projecting the demographic impact of Syrian migration in a rapidly ageing society, Germany</title>
      <link>/publication/jgs2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/jgs2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package CIM Compositional Impact of Migration</title>
      <link>/publication/rcim2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/rcim2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efectos cambiantes de la migración sobre el crecimiento, la estructura demográfica y la segregación residencial en ciudades grandes. El caso de Santiago, Chile, 1977-2017</title>
      <link>/publication/cepal2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/cepal2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighbourhood change and trajectories of inequality in Britain, 1971-2011</title>
      <link>/publication/policybrief2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/policybrief2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing the extent and pace of the contemporary trend of migration decline in Europe</title>
      <link>/publication/rsa2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/rsa2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is internal migration reshaping metropolitan populations in Latin America? A new method and new evidence</title>
      <link>/publication/ps2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ps2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from the evaluation of past local area population forecasts</title>
      <link>/publication/prpr2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/prpr2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To travel or not to travel. ‘Weather’ is the question. Modelling the effect of local weather conditions on bus ridership</title>
      <link>/publication/trc2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/trc2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>¿Contribuye la migración interna a reducir la segregación residencial? El caso de Santiago de Chile 1977-2002</title>
      <link>/publication/relap2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/relap2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of migration on education-job mismatch. Evidence from overseas graduates in Australia</title>
      <link>/publication/bookcp2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/bookcp2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration of Young Human Capital?</title>
      <link>/post/si_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/si_post/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-the-migration-of-young-educated-people-important&#34;&gt;Why is the migration of young educated people important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human capital is a key ingredient of economic development and productivity. Regions attracting educated individuals experience economic growth and enjoy high-status of social wellbeing, while areas affected by net migration losses of human capital struggle to sustain a vibrant local economy. Young educated individuals are highly mobile and comprise a important component of the workforce. Spatial mobility of young educated individuals generates differentiated outcomes across the urban hierarchy. Rural areas tend to lose young population, creating pressures to attract and retain young educated individuals to help redress accelerating ageing populations and replenishing labour gaps. By contrast, larger metropolitan areas operate as magnets enticing the ‘best’ and the ‘brightest’ spurring local economic development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-new-and-are-our-aims&#34;&gt;What is new and are our aims?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recently published Special Issue, we draw on a select group of international leading experts in human capital mobility from a variety of countries, including Australia, China, Italy, the Netherlands, the UK, the USA and Sweden – and seek to address key outstanding issues associated with the spatial mobility of young educated people. In particular, we we draw on longitudinal data sets so that we can begin to examine longer windows of time and better capture mobility sequences over the transition from school through university to the labour market and how they intersect with their educational and occupational pathways and impacts on places. We argue that understanding these trajectories will augment our capacity to guide regional development policy on the attraction and retention of human capital and develop more appropriate policy strategies to address skill shortages, particularly in rural areas, and enhance individual employment outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to the editorial of our Special Issue is &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00168-017-0845-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The changing composition and fortunes of overseas graduates in Australia. The case of Chinese and Indian graduates</title>
      <link>/publication/bookcp2019_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/bookcp2019_2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The drivers of long-distance commuting in Chile. The role of spatial distribution of economic activities</title>
      <link>/publication/bookcp2019_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/bookcp2019_1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Changing Impacts of Internal Migration on Residential Socio-Economic Segregation in the Greater Santiago</title>
      <link>/publication/iussp2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/iussp2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Impact of Internal Migration on Population Redistribution in Europe</title>
      <link>/publication/ersa2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ersa2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Labor Market Areas for Chile</title>
      <link>/publication/region2017_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/region2017_1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CHilean Internal Migration (CHIM) database. Temporally consistent spatial data for the analysis of human mobility</title>
      <link>/publication/region2017_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/region2017_2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing internal migration across the countries of Latin America. A multidimensional approach</title>
      <link>/publication/plosone2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/plosone2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do we define functional labour market areas?</title>
      <link>/post/llma_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/llma_post/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We all know that spatial analyses based on administrative boundaries to understand labour market activity are questionable, because of the modifiable areal unit problem (MAUP) and measurement issues, leading to spurious causal relationships, misguided policy recommendations and complex model specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last two decades, there has been a growing literature concerning the delimitation of Functional Labour Market Areas (FLMAs). They are empirically delimited based on commuting (travel-to-work) flow data between Basic Territorial Units (BTUs; eg. communes, municipalities or counties), which are often the finest level of geography at which data are available. The trick here is that there are two conflicting objectives. On the one hand, we want to create FMLAs that are composed of BTUs with strong commuting links i.e. strong cohesion or inner integration. On the other, we want FLMAs comprised of BTUs with weak or no commuting links with other FLMAs i.e. higher self-containment or external perfection. Large FLMAs lead to higher overall levels of self-containment but lower levels of cohesion from a certain threshold. Finding an appropriate balance between self-containment and cohesion is thus critical and challenging task for FMLAs delineation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have recently published a paper (Casado-Díaz, Martínez-Bernabéu and Rowe 2017) on a novel methodology based on evolutionary computational algorithms to delineate FLMAs for Chile. Why Chile? Because we wanted to try out this new methodology on a unusual geography and Chile provides just that; and, because I am Chilean! We compared the performance of our approach to the most widely used methodology for official LMA delimitation, the travel-to-work areas (TTWAs) method, in terms of computational efficiency. We also compared the suitability of the resulting FLMAs against administrative areas and TTWAs based on expert local knowledge and misallocation of BTUs. Normally BTUs are allocated to FLMAs with which they have weak links and need to be reassign to a different FLMA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying our algorithm, we proposed a set of 62 FLMAs, which we called “GEA-LMA”: Grouping Evolutionary Algorithm-Labour Market Areas. The figure below presents these areas against provinces (second administrative level of geography in Chile) and TTWA-LMAs. Overall, the proposed areas outperformed administrative areas and TTWA-LMAs, in terms of self-containment and computing efficiency, providing a more appropriate framework for the analysis of spatial labour market activity. In the paper, we suggested two methodological improvements in order to: (1) produce a better conciliation between the different objectives of regionalization; (2) improve the local quality of the final regionalization by reducing the number of misallocated BTUs and the need to make adjustments to achieve a definitive regionalization; and, (3) increase the efficiency of the evolutionary algorithm by reducing the computational time required to find the optimal regionalisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./body.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34; /&gt;
Figure 1. Maps of local self-containment: provinces, TTWA-LMAs and GEA-LMAs (labels for regional capital cities are displayed).
Note: Local self-containment of an area is calculated as the minimum value of the share of residents of a BTU working within its considered region, and the share of jobs of that BTU occupied by its residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our paper is open access and our code is available with the paper if you would like to implement our approach! Get it now from Spatial Economic Analysis on this link!: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17421772.2017.1273541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17421772.2017.1273541&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casado-Díaz J. M., Martínez-Bernabéu, L. &amp;amp; Rowe, F. 2017. An evolutionary approach to the delimitation of labour market areas: an empirical application for Chile. Pages 1-25.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An evolutionary approach to the delimitation of labour market areas. An empirical application for Chile</title>
      <link>/publication/sea2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/sea2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special issue on youth and graduate migration</title>
      <link>/publication/ars2017ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ars2017ed/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The returns to migration and human capital accumulation pathways. non-metropolitan youth in the school-to-work transition</title>
      <link>/publication/ars2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ars2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impacts of Policy Change on Overseas Human Capital in Australia. The Implementation of the 485 Graduate Visa Scheme</title>
      <link>/publication/bookcp2016_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/bookcp2016_1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website builder for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a free website with Academic using Markdown, Jupyter, or RStudio. Choose a beautiful color theme and build anything with the Page Builder - over 40 &lt;em&gt;widgets&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;themes&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;language packs&lt;/em&gt; included!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the latest &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/#expo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;view the &lt;strong&gt;showcase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;#install&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Started&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the &lt;strong&gt;documentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask a question&lt;/strong&gt; on the forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👥 &lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.chat/academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chat with the &lt;strong&gt;community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐦 Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/source_themes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@source_themes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23MadeWithAcademic&amp;amp;src=typd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#MadeWithAcademic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💡 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Request a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; or report a &lt;strong&gt;bug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⬆️ &lt;strong&gt;Updating?&lt;/strong&gt; View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;❤️ &lt;strong&gt;Support development&lt;/strong&gt; of Academic:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;☕️ &lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate a coffee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💵 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Become a backer on &lt;strong&gt;Patreon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🖼️ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/neutreno/works/34387919-academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Decorate your laptop or journal with an Academic &lt;strong&gt;sticker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👕 &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.threadless.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wear the &lt;strong&gt;T-shirt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👩‍💻 &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/contribute/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;














&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Academic is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Academic is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/themes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 15+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic comes with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Alternatively, visitors can  choose their preferred mode - click the sun/moon icon in the top right of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code&gt;params.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/themes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/customization/#custom-theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;customizable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-admin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to import publications from BibTeX or import assets for an offline site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-scripts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Scripts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Scripts to help migrate content to new versions of Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-web-browser&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;install on your computer using &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;install on your computer by downloading the &lt;strong&gt;ZIP files&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;install on your computer with &lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/get-started/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;personalize and deploy your new site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the Update Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Mobility Patterns of Overseas Graduates in Australia</title>
      <link>/publication/bookcp2016_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/bookcp2016_2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the effects of Australian policy changes on human capital. The role of a graduate visa scheme</title>
      <link>/publication/epc2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/epc2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in attitudes towards immigration between Australia and Germany. The role of immigration policy</title>
      <link>/publication/cops2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/cops2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing post-school pathways and outcomes. Melbourne and regional students</title>
      <link>/publication/arc2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/arc2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attraction and Retention. Education and labour force pathways of metropolitan and regional school leavers in Victoria</title>
      <link>/publication/arc2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/arc2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinants of post-school choices of young people. The workforce, university or vocational studies?</title>
      <link>/publication/arc2014_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/arc2014_4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where are the overseas graduates staying on? Overseas graduate migration and rural attachment in Australia</title>
      <link>/publication/ag2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ag2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labour market outcomes and educational and occupational pathways of young movers starting off in regional Victoria</title>
      <link>/publication/arc2014_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/arc2014_3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labour market outcomes and main educational and occupational pathways of young Victorians</title>
      <link>/publication/arc2014_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/arc2014_2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patterns and sequences of mobility</title>
      <link>/publication/arc2014_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/arc2014_1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytical approach and data issues</title>
      <link>/publication/arc2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/arc2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobility Patterns of Overseas Human Capital in Australia. The role of a ‘new’ graduate visa scheme and rural development policy</title>
      <link>/publication/ag2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ag2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The geography and determinants of regional human capital in eight Latin American and Caribbean countries</title>
      <link>/publication/bookcp2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/bookcp2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The forecast accuracy of local government area population projections. A case study of Queensland</title>
      <link>/publication/ajrs2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ajrs2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
